After rendering major military achievements in the war against the State of Wei, Xin has become a Thousand-Man General.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）魏国(ぎこく)との戦で武功を上げ
晴れて千人将になった信(しん)
But with the territory they have to protect enlarged,
だが 拡大した領土を
守る前線地帯での戦いで―
飛信(ひしん)隊は連戦連敗
the Feixin Unit has been suffering consecutive losses on the front lines.
ついに 千人将降格の危機にまで
追い込まれてしまう
And now, Xin has been driven to the point of being in danger of losing his title of Thousand-Man General.
After learning that the cause of it was their strategy,
その原因が戦略にあると
知った蒙恬(もうてん)は 王都 咸陽(かんよう)から―
Meng Tian called his little brother, the outstanding tactician Meng Yi, from the royal capital of Xianyang.
飛び切りの軍師である弟 蒙毅(もうき)を
呼び寄せた
Or so he thought...
…はずだった
But the one that appeared before Xin and the others was...
だが 信たちの前に現れたのは…
（信）
な… なんで お前が ここに？
Wh-Why are you here?!
（兵士たち）えっ？ 知り合い？
Y-You know him?!
（貂(てん)）
ハハハッ… やっぱり驚いたか
I thought you'd be surprised.
正直 こういう形で
お前の前に現れるのは―
I honestly thought I wouldn't show up like this for quite some time.
ずっと先のことだと思ってたから
俺自身も ちょっと驚いてんだけど
Even I was kinda surprised this happened.
But I guess it's not really the time for saying stuff like that.
そんなことも
言ってらんない状況だからな
I'm here to help, Xin!
（貂）助けに来てやったぞ 信！
Diao!
貂！
Trial and Resolve
Th-Then...
蒙恬の弟の代理で お前が来た？
You're saying you came here in place of Meng Tian's little brother...?
So this person is going to be our strategist?
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）…てことは
こいつがウチの軍師になんのか？
（ざわめき）
（兵士）え～っ？ ホントかよ？
No way, that's just a kid!
（去亥(きょがい)）ざけんな こんなガキが！
しかも こいつ…
You've gotta be kidding me. This brat?!
And this person's...
（信）まあ そりゃ後回しでいいや
とにかく久しぶりだな 貂
Well, we can figure that out later.
Anyhow, nice to see you again, Diao.
さすがに背が伸びてらぁ！
You sure have gotten taller.
Looks like that straw coat's on its last legs.
その蓑(みの) もう限界だろう
ハハッ！ なんだよ
Aw man, your face is starting to look like a girl's!
お前 女みてえな顔つきに
なっちまってよ！
ハハハッ！
どうすりゃ そうなんだよ？
What's with that?!
ちゃんとメシ食ってたか？
ハハハハッ…
Have you been eating right?
Uh, what're you talking about?
（去亥）何言ってんだ？ お前
どう見たって そいつ 女だろう
That's pretty obviously a woman.
信と会うの どんだけぶりだっけ？
How long's it been since I last seen Xin...?
メチャクチャ成長しちゃったから
さすがに もう…
I've grown a whole lot so I guess I'll have to...
今更 悩むなよ！
I can't get upset about it now!
そういうのも含めて―
I'm trying to get my feelings in order!
気持ちの整理は
済ませてきただろうが！
ええっ… 女？
A woman?
…て んなわけねえだろう！
No way!
（兵士たち）アア…
（信）何言ってんだ 去亥！
The hell're you talkin' about, Qu Hai?
He still hasn't gotten it?
バレてない？
それはそれで なんか…
Well, that's kind of...
No, I need to settle this.
いや もう うやむやには しない
What matters most right now is whether I can function as a strategist here or not.
今いちばん大事なのは―
俺が軍師として
ここで やっていけるかどうかだ
I came here with the resolve not to go back to Xianyang.
俺は もう咸陽には戻らない覚悟で
ここに来たんだから
信！
（信）えっ？
Xin!
What that man said isn't wrong.
（貂）その人の言っていることは
間違いじゃないよ
Sorry, Xin.
悪い 信… 実は俺 女の子
Truth is, I'm a girl.
…てことで 改めて よろしく
So, let me reintroduce myself.
黙ってて悪かったよ 信　でも…
I'm sorry for not telling you, Xin.
But...
Diao... So even you
（信）貂 だから お前まで…
なに ふざけてんだよ！
are screwing with me, aren't you?
（めくる音）
（尾平(びへい)たち）アア…
Huh?
あれ？
Fuck off, creep!
ざけんな てめえ！
（道清(どうせい)）うん？
Oh, Dao Qing. You look well.
（間永(かんえい)）おお 道清 元気そうだのぅ
What?! Even you've come here...?
（道清）
なんと！ あなた方まで ここに
Yes. I've heard that Lijing could become an opening to take back Shanyang.
おう　ここ里井(りせい)が山陽(さんよう)奪還の
突破口になると聞いてのぅ
（道清）ハハハッ…
それだけではありますまい
I doubt that's all.
ハハッ… お見通しらしいぞ
無論 狙いは飛信隊だ
You've seen right through me.
Of course, my target is the Feixin Unit.
They did us quite a disservice in the battle at Shanyang.
（道清）山陽の戦いでは
ヤツらに世話になりましたからなぁ
（間永）ああ
輪虎(りんこ)将軍が討たれたときから―
Yes. When General Lun Hu was slain, the central army lost all its power.
中央軍は力を失っていった
If we had been by the general's side, the war would not have ended as it did.
（氷鬼(ひょうき)）
我らの配置が将軍のそばであれば
ああは ならなかった
飛信隊に
苦汁をなめさせられた我ら３人
The Feixin Unit caused us three quite some trouble.
We came here to settle the score.
借りを返す時が来たというわけだ
You came at a good time. The Feixin Unit isn't doing well at the moment.
都合がいいことに
今 飛信隊は絶不調と来ています
フッ…
それはそれで張り合いがないが
In that case, it might not even be worth doing... Ah well.
まあ よかろう
In this fight, we will cut that accursed Feixin Unit to pieces!
この戦いで
憎き飛信隊 信を切り刻むぞ！
ウワッ！
（翼(よく)）おっと… どこに置く？
Woah, there.
Where does this go?
Um, next to that.
えっと…
あっ じゃ そこの横に
（翼）
ここね… ほかのは どうする？
Here?
What about the others?
（貂）あっ じゃ これを同じ所に
（翼）あいよ
Um, put these in the same place.
Gotcha.
（貂）あっ それは こっちに…
それは外に置いといて
Ah, that goes here.
And put that one outside.
（翼）あいよ
Got it.
（去亥）おい 信 本気で
あんな小娘 隊に入れんのかよ？
Hey, Xin. Are you really taking that little girl into the unit?
Say, how could he have not realized that if he lived with her?
（兵士Ａ）
…つうか 一緒に暮らしてて
なんで気づかねえんだ？
（兵士Ｂ）うちらの隊長
やっぱ 相当バカなんだな
Our captain's pretty stupid, isn't he?
（信）聞こえてんぞ！
（兵士たち）アッ…
I can hear you!
ハァ… 考えてみりゃ…
Now that I think about it...
I can't say that nothing comes to mind.
思い当たる節がねえわけじゃねえ
Diao! How bout we go take a piss together?!
貂 連れションすっか？
（貂）１人で行け ボケ！
Go on your own, moron!
How 'bout a bath?
（信）暑いなぁ　水浴びすっか？
（貂）裸で来んな ボケ！
Stay away from me when you're naked, moron!
貂 これって食えっか？
（貂）いきなり来んな ボケ！
Diao, can you eat these?
Give me some warning, moron!
Geez, why was she a girl, too?
だからって なんで あいつまで女…
What the hell's going on recently?
一体 どうなってんだ？ 最近は
Is that just the times we're in? These days...
あれか？
時代が そうさせてんのか？ 時代が
Ah, well it doesn't really matter.
まあいいか 別に
弟が妹になったみてえなもんだし
It's like my little brother is my little sister now.
It's not a big...
大して…
（馬の駆ける音）
Emergency report! Emergency report!
（騎兵）急報！ 急報！
The enemy is on the move!
（騎兵）敵が動いてきた！
刑山(けいざん)の麓に1,000の敵！
An enemy of 1,000 has been spotted
at the base of Mount Xing!
They seem to be heading this way!
こちらに向かってきてるそうだ！
What?!
なんだって！
They're coming already, huh?
もう来やがったのか！
（騎兵）はっ！
Yes, sir!
（貂）“麓”じゃ分からない！
（信たち）うん？
What do you mean "bast of the mountain"?!
There are three paths from there!
あそこには３つの道がある
崖沿いと川沿いと山道の どれだ？
Did they go along the cliffs, along the river, or on the mountain path?!
崖沿いだ！
Along the cliffs!
How many mounted soldiers do they have?
（貂）騎馬の数は？
（騎兵）そこまでは分からん
I don't know that much!
…て 誰だ？
And, who are you?
Spread out a map!
（貂）地図を広げろ！
Send scouts to Mount Zhen and Mount Ba!
振山(しんざん)と巴山(はざん)に物見を走らせろ！
There may be other enemies working with them!
ほかに連動している敵が
いるかもしれない
Diao, how is it you know about the area?
（信）貂 お前 なんで この辺の…
来る途中で 全部 頭に入れてきた
I learned it all on my way here.
What're you doing? We need a map...
何してんの！ 早く 地図！
Whadda ya think yer doin', little girl?
（田永(でんえい)）
なに出しゃばってんだ 小娘が！
ここはガキの来る所じゃねえぞ
こら！
This isn't a place for kids, dammit!
目障りだ
ぶっ飛ばされる前に うせろ ボケ！
You're an eyesore.
Get lost before I knock your lights out, moron.
（尾平）田永のヤツ マジ脅し
That Tian Yong is seriously threatening her.
She's gonna start crying...
（兵士Ｃ）泣くぞ あの娘
（兵士Ｄ）かわいそうに…
I feel bad for her...
ウザッ…
（田永）なっ…
You're annoying.
Wh-
What did you say?
なんだと…
What'd you say, asshole?!
なんだと こらぁ！
新参軍師がやっかみに遭うってのは
十分 知ってるよ
I'm well aware of the jealousy against new strategists.
だけど今は そんなこと
言ってる場合じゃないだろう！
But now isn't the time for this!
（貂）山陽にとって―
You know how important this place is for Shanyang, right?!
ここが どれだけ重要な場所か
ちゃんと分かってるのか？
You know that I'm here because if you keep at this the way you've been doing it, there'll be irreparable damage, right?!
今までどおりやっちゃ
取り返しのつかないことになるから
俺が来たんだろう！
Y-You brat, get lost!
ガ… ガキは すっ込んでろ！
Knock it off, Tian You.
（信）やめとけ 田永
But...!
だがよ！
（信）俺が話す
I'll talk to her.
Diao, I know that you seriously want to be our strategist
（信）貂…
俺は
お前が真剣に軍師になりたくて―
and that you studied hard for it.
勉強してたのは知ってる
だけど 実際…
But to be honest, I don't know just how much you can do right now.
今 お前が どんだけのことが
できるのかは分かんねえ
そのお前に―
So I can't just pass the whole task of directing the unit to you.
いきなり この隊の指揮を
丸投げするわけには いかねえんだ
You understand, right?
分かるな？
I'll allow you to travel with the headquarters, but the unit's organization is going to stay the same as always.
本陣への同行は許すが
体制は とにかく今までどおりだ
分かったよ 信…
I understand, Xin.
All units, prepare to sortie! Hurry!
（渕(えん)）各隊 出陣準備！ 急げ！
（兵士）よし 急げ！
（兵士）よっしゃ！
Okay, hurry!
Hurry, go!
Hurry!
（兵士）急げ！
入れたと思ったら
また出さなきゃだな
I thought you were in, but I guess you had to leave again, huh?
Oh, it's you. Uh...
（貂）あっ さっきの… えっと…
It's Yi.
翼だ
（貂）翼さん
Mr. Yi.
Okay then...
（翼）さてと…
Ah, I'll do it.
あっ 俺 やるよ
Gangway.
（翼）どいた どいた！
よいしょっと…
There we are.
Hang in there.
頑張んなよ
（貂）えっ？
After seeing Vice Captain Qiang Lei, I've realized that it really doesn't matter if you're a man or a woman.
羌瘣(きょうかい)副長を見てて
男も女も関係ないって分かったしな
それに…
And...
Ah, nothing.
いいや
（貂）なに？
What is it?
You look kinda like how my wife back home looked in her younger days.
故郷(くに)に残してきた嫁の
若いころに ちょっと似てる
Or maybe age-wise, you're more like my daughter?
いや 年からすりゃ 娘のほうかな？
どっちにしても かわいいんだ
（貂）なんだ そりゃ…
Well either way, you're pretty cute.
Ah, what the hell?
ハハッ…
まあ だから 頑張れってこった
Anyhow, you've gotta keep trying.
（伝令Ｂ）報告！ 田永隊 苦戦中！
Report!
The Tian You Unit is fighting a hard battle!
なに？
What?!
（伝令Ｂ）応援を求めています
（信）よし！
They are requesting backup!
Okay!
The Long You Unit is requesting aid as well!
（伝令Ｃ）
竜有隊も同様です！ 応援を！
We need to send in Wei Ping and Mr. Ze's units right away!
すぐに尾平と澤(たく)さんの隊を送り出せ
（渕）はっ！
Yes, sir!
（貂）待て！
Wait!
Those two units don't need help.
その２隊に助けは要らない
（信）どういうことだよ？
What do ya mean?!
（貂）２隊の場所は
外せない要地じゃない
Those two units aren't fighting in strategically critical locations.
If they're having trouble, then just have them retreat to the thicket behind them and regroup.
苦戦しているなら
後方の茂みに逃れて立て直せばいい
それより危ういのは―
The more critical areas are the places Pei Lang, Chong Yuan, and Tian You are protecting.
沛浪(はいろう) 崇原(すうげん) 田有(でんゆう)の３隊の持ち場だ
If the enemy claims these areas,
（貂）この場所を敵に取られると
周辺の隊との連絡路を
断たれるおそれがある
there's a possibility we may lose our channels of communication with the units in those areas.
If the enemy catches onto that, it's likely they'll attack those areas with full force.
敵が もし そのことに気づけば
全力で攻めてくるはずだ
応援部隊は
ここに回しておいたほうがいい
We're better off sending reinforcement units to those.
To Pei Lang and the others' units?
沛浪たちの所へ？
しかし そこからは何の連絡も…
But we haven't gotten any word from them at...
（信）貂！
Diao!
お前は口出ししねえ約束だろうが！
You promised not to butt in!
I'm just talkin' to myself.
独り言
（信）クッ…
（渕）信どの どうしましょうか？
Lord Xin. What do you think?
どうもしねえ！
さっき言ったとおりだ
There's nothing to think about! Just do what I said!
Send reinforcements to Tian You's unit!
田永たちに応援を送れ
（渕）はっ！
Yes, sir!
But that strategy had an unexpected consequence as well.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
だが その作戦は またも裏目に出た
貂の言葉どおり―
Just as Diao had said, the enemy concentrated a considerable number of units on Pei Lang and the others' stations.
敵は相当数の部隊を
沛浪たちの持ち場に集中させたのだ
（崇原）強い！
何だ？ この魏国軍の強さは！
They're strong! What's going on?!
Why is this State of Wei unit so strong?!
この敵は
今までの相手とは全く格が違う！
This enemy is on a completely different level from the enemies we've fought so far!
Emergency report! Emergency report!
（騎兵）急報！ 急報！
（騎兵）
沛浪 崇原 田有の３隊が崩壊！
The Pei Lang, Chong Yuan, and Tian You units are breaking down!
The enemy has taken their encampments!
敵に陣を取られました！
（信）なに！
What?!
敵に こちらの連絡路を全て断たれ
ほかの隊の動静が不明に…
The enemy has cut off all of our channels of communication, so the state of the other units are unknown!
What?!
なんだと！
（渕）信どの…
Lord Xin!
Bring my horse here!
（信）俺の馬を ここに！
俺が取り戻してやる！
I'm gonna get those places back!
Stop!
（貂）やめろ！
The enemies will already have traps setup.
もう敵のワナが張られている
Xin, seriously, let me step in.
信 やっぱり代わろう
Xin
Hurry up and decide.
（貂）早く決めろ
急がないと―
If we don't hurry, with those small units separated, they'll be utterly wiped out!
バラバラになった小隊たちは
根こそぎ刈られるぞ
（信）ンンッ…
（貂）信！
Xin!
Okay.
（信）分かったよ…
It seems he's not coming.
来ませぬな
（間永）
妙だな… 飛信隊 信の性格なら―
That's odd. Knowing Feixin Unit Xin's character,
I thought he would come here to take this area back himself.
直ちに 自ら
この地を取り戻しに来ると思ったが
Have there been any changes in the Feixin Unit headquarters?
飛信隊本陣の様子に変化は？
No outstanding reports have come in.
（魏兵Ａ）
特に報告は入っておりません
Now then...
（間永）さて…
Emergency report! Emergency report!
（伝令）急報！ 急報！
The enemy headquarters has... suddenly disappeared!
（伝令）敵本陣が
忽然(こつぜん)と姿を消したとのことです
Disappeared?
消えた？
So they're finally headed this way, eh?
ようやく こっちへ来るのか！
No.
いや…
（間永）うん？
味方を捜して 立て直しを
図るつもりかもしれません
They may be searching for their allies and are planning a regroup.
Spread out a search team!
捜索網を敷け！
今 敵本陣は孤立し 100人程度だ
Right now, the enemy headquarters is alone as only 100 men!
見つければ
簡単に たたきつぶせるぞ！
If we find them, crushing them will be an easy task!
オワーッ！
Keep a close watch on your footing!
（兵士１）足元 よく見ろよ
（尾平）アア… うるせえ！
Ow... Shut up!
（信）なんだって こんな密林を？
Why're we heading into this dense forest...?
If we take roads, the enemy will find us.
（貂）道を行けば 敵に見つかる！
とにかく全力で走れ！
Just focus on running as fast as you can!
This is a match of speed!
これは速さの勝負だ
Just as the State of Wei Army's strategist, Bing Gui, had predicted,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
魏国軍師 氷鬼の読みどおり―
the Feixin Unit headquarters was following Diao's instructions
飛信隊本陣は 貂の指示に従い
散っている仲間の隊を集めて
疾走していた
and scampering to gather their scattered comrades.
Meanwhile...
一方…
Don't let your guard down!
（魏兵Ｂ）
油断するな！ ヤツらは近いぞ
They're close!
Slaughter them all!
（魏兵Ｃ）皆殺しだ！
Against that, Bing Gui had spread out a large-scale encircling net.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）それに対して
氷鬼は大規模な包囲網を展開した
State of Wei Army Encircling Net
Wei
しかし その包囲網が
敷かれたときには 既に―
But when that encircling net laid out,
Diao and the others had already gotten through to the back of it.
貂たちは
その裏へと抜けていたのである
Feixin Unit
（歓声）
（信）やったな 貂！
Nice job, Diao!
I still haven't done anything.
まだ何もやっていない…
本番は これからだ
The real thing starts now.
We're going to remake the headquarters on the other side of these hills!
この先の丘に本陣を置き直す！
Let me see a map!
地図を見せて
散ってる各隊の居場所を示すから
捜してきて！
I'll point out where the scattered units are, so go look for them!
A girl?
（蒙恬）女の子？
（蒙毅）はい
Yes.
I'm not trying to cover for her,
（蒙毅）別に
彼女をかばうわけではないですが
but with regards to strategists, gender doesn't seem to make a difference.
（蒙毅）軍師にとって
性別は さほど問題ではないかと…
Well, I guess.
いや まあね… ここさえ切れれば
As long as they're sharp up here.
I guarantee that.
それは 僕が保証します
She already received master's special strategist approval.
何しろ 彼女は―
既に 先生の特別軍師認可を
もらっていますから
Master's?
先生の？
（蒙毅）兄上以来の早期認可ですよ
She was approved faster than anyone since you.
At the school, the only one that's able to compete with her in Strategic Go is me.
学校では 彼女と軍略囲碁で
まともに戦えるのは僕だけです
なるほどね
I see...
（蒙恬）それじゃ あとは…
After that, all there is is whether she has the hostile character of a strategist.
軍師としての
適性があるかどうかだな
Without that, no matter how much talent you have,
これがないと
どんなに才能があっても―
軍師として活躍することはできない
you won't be able to flourish as a strategist.
For some reason, He Liao Diao has the strength of already having real-world experience.
（蒙毅）河了貂(かりょうてん)は―
訳あって 既に実戦を
経験しているという強みはあります
…が しかし
この問題ばかりは やはり―
But... I suppose we won't see any problems until we see her results.
結果を見てみないと
分かりませんね
（慶(けい)）オッ… いるいる！
田永隊 連れてきたぞ！
Oh, there they are!
I brought the Tian You Unit!
So you guys are okay?!
（去亥）
おお！ お前らも無事だったか！
ハハハハッ！
本陣移動とは大胆だな
Moving the headquarters was a bold move!
That Xin's pretty good once in a while.
信のヤツも
たまには やるじゃねえか
（去亥）信じゃねえ
（田永）うん？
It wasn't Xin.
（去亥）
今 指揮してんのは小娘軍師だ
The one directing things right now is that girl strategist.
Wh-What?!
な… なに？
（竜有）お前らだけじゃねえ
It's not just you guys.
She found our totally isolated units wandering around as well.
（竜有）完全に孤軍となって
さまよってた―
俺らの隊も見つけやがった
（田有）俺のところもだ
（松左(しょうさ)）俺の隊も
Mine, too.
My unit, too.
（沛浪）読みだけで―
Just from looking at the situation she correctly guessed the locations of every unit and gathered us all together.
散ってた全部隊の居場所を
言い当てて 集結させちまったんだ
It looks like that brat's no ordinary girl.
あのガキ どうやら
ただの小娘じゃねえみてえだぞ
来た！
Here they come.
A strategist's hostility is always tested on their first campaign.
（蒙毅）軍師は必ず
初陣で その適性を試される
適性？
Hostility?
まだ机上だけの策士である我々は
As strategists that've only worked on tables,
we don't understand the fear of actually standing on a battlefield.
実際に戦場に降り立つ恐怖を
知らない
Can you keep your cool while the enemy will draw on you if you don't kill these ones?
こちらを殺さんと敵が迫りくる中
冷静でいられるのか？
冷静に―
Can you calmly cause people to kill one another?
人と人を殺し合わせることが
できるのか？
日ごろ 軽々しく
扱っている このひと駒には―
These game pieces we handle so frivolously on a daily basis
数百人もの生の人間の命が
宿っている
contain hundreds of human lives in them.
The fear of an actual battle is more than anything we can imagine.
想像の上をいく実戦の恐怖
それに のまれて 何もできずに
つぶれる軍師見習いは―
There are many strategist apprentices that are swallowed by that and crushed because they can't manage to do anything.
数多く いるんだ
（信）貂 敵が見えた！
Diao, the enemy's in sight!
アア… 貂？
Diao?
With all my experience in them,
（貂）いくつかの経験で―
実戦ってのは
それなりに知ってるつもりでいた
I thought I knew what real battles were like.
But this is different!
でも これは違う
熱気と殺気が
風に乗って まとわりつく
Their enthusiasm and bloodlust are riding on the wind and coiling around me!
This is definitely the first time I've felt this suffocated.
確かに
こんなに息苦しいのは初めてだ
I see...
そうか…
これが戦場の空気か
This is the air of a battlefield, huh?
Like hell I'm going to let this swallow me
戦う前から これかよ…
before I even fight!
のまれるものか！
Hey, Diao!
おい 貂！
（貂）分かってる
Got it!
We're starting!
始めるぞ！ 配置に就け！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
Take your positions!
（貂）俺が戦場をのんでやるんだ！
I will swallow the battlefield!
ほう…
ハハハハッ！
ヤツらも動いてきたぞ
They've moved, too.
Send the Dao Qing Unit forward.
道清隊を前に
（魏兵Ｄ）ははっ！
道清を？
Dao Qing?
That's an elite Thousand-Man Unit. It'll be all over at once.
あれは千人隊で精鋭ぞろいだ
一気に終わるぞ
Then so be it.
それなら それで
（道清）道清隊
先陣を預かったぞ！ 名誉と思え！
Dao Qing Unit!
You have the lead!
Consider it an honor!
The Feixin Unit headquarters got behind us before I had laid out my encircling net
俺が包囲網を敷く前に
飛信隊本陣は裏へ抜けていた
そして
散開していた兵とも合流していた
and they joined up with their scattered soldiers.
この迅速な立て直し…
This rapid reorganization...
明らかに 何者かが
参謀として隊に加入している
It is clear that someone has joined their unit as a staff officer!
Here we go!
いくぞ！
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
I will measure what level of strategist it is with this move!
（氷鬼）どの程度の軍師か
この一手で測らせてもらう
Here they come!
（田孝(でんこう)）来た 敵先鋒隊(せんぽうたい)！
The enemy vanguard!
There's between 800 and 1,000.
800から1,000
そのうち騎兵は およそ200！
Among them, about 200 are mounted soldiers!
あっ 私
補佐役となりました田孝です
Ah, I was placed as your assistant. My name is Tian Xiao.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Tian Xiao.
（貂）よろしく 田孝さん
騎兵は300 歩兵700だよ
（田孝）はい！
There are 300 mounted soldiers and 700 foot soldiers.
Yes, ma'am!
They've suddenly moved 1,000 of their 4,000 soldiers.
全軍4,000のうちの1,000を
いきなり動かしてきた
And this is an elite unit!
しかも あれは精鋭部隊か！
They're not trying to hurry the battle.
戦を急いでいるということじゃない
That is a tactic to see what our reaction is like!
あれは
こっちの反応を見ようとしている
They want to measure my capacity!
俺の力量を測る気だ！
You've got it!
望むところだ！
全軍 そのまま待機！
All units, stay on standby!
What?! We're not going...?
（信）えっ？
なんだよ 行くんじゃねえのかよ！
いきなり1,000対1,000の戦い
It's a sudden battle of 1,000 on 1,000.
といっても
ここで戦力を失い過ぎると―
But if we lose too much fighting strength,
we won't be able to fight the remaining 3,000.
残りの3,000と戦えなくなる
あれは策にハメて
効率よく倒さないといけない
We need to setup a plan and defeat them efficiently!
（田孝）河了貂！
迎撃しないと 敵が どんどん…
He Liao Diao, unless we meet them, the enemy will keep getting closer...
いいんだ！
（田孝）えっ？
It's all right!
They can't see from over there,
（貂）向こうからは見えていない
but there are a lot of forked paths in the State of Wei's way!
魏国軍の行く手には
いくつもの岐路があることを！
ここで 一気に…
Here, we can inter the entire thousand of the enemy's vanguard!
敵先鋒隊1,000を葬る！
Preview
Outwit
End